gbgplc.com 2019-04-11

# Legal | GBG

**What personal information GBG collects and why**

When you apply online for a position with GBG we will use the information you provide to assist in the recruitment and selection process. There is information we require in order to process your application, which within the software is depicted as mandatory fields. GBG may also seek additional information from other sources, for example, by using your references in the final stages of the recruitment process.

You have the opportunity to provide information in relation to additional adjustments required for the recruitment process to assist you. This is to ensure we enable all individuals to compete on equal terms. You may choose to provide some special category data here, such as ethnicity, religious beliefs or medical conditions, but it is not required and can be provided at a later date.

**Purpose and legal basis for processing**

Our purpose for processing your data in the event of a job application is to assess your suitability for the role. We rely on Article 6(1)(b) of the GDPR, which relates to processing necessary to perform a contract or to take steps at your request before entering into a contract.

With regard to any special category data you provide, we collect this information to monitor equality and diversity to ensure we comply with legislation such as the Equality Act 2010. We therefore rely on compliance with a legal obligation under Article 6(1)(c) of the GDPR as the lawful basis for processing and Article 9(2)(a) of the GDPR, since we collect such special category data for the purposes of carrying out our obligations in the field of employment.

**Data retention**

Information provided on the application form and any information obtained from other sources will be retained in all cases in hard copy format and/or electronically only for as long as is required for the purposes of:

  * the administration of your application
  * future consideration where applicable (you will be notified separately if your application details will be retained for this purpose and provided with the opportunity to request deletion)
  * if your application is successful this will form the basis of your employment records
  * discharging any legal or regulatory requirements

Your data is retained for 3 months within be/hired, our internal HR platform, then it is automatically deleted. If you would like your data deleted sooner, please contact compliance@gbgplc.com so we can raise this as a request for Access UK Ltd to complete on our behalf.

If your recruitment process goes beyond 3 months, you will be aware of this, with your personal data then held by GBG for the duration of the recruitment process.

If you are successful with your application, the personal data you have supplied to us will form part of your employment record.

**Use of data processors**

GBG will share your information with third party service partners, who are acting on behalf of GBG as our data processor:

**Access UK Ltd** : provides GBG with the software which controls the be/hired process. This is hosted in the UK. GBG is unable to change the questions which have been asked or the process within the system you are taken through. Whilst Access UK controls the “how” from a software perspective and hosts this platform, your personal data is gathered by GBG as the data controller, so we decide on why this is processed, who it is shared with, etc. The aCloud Recruitment Team at Access UK (Deployment/Development & support) appoints one individual in the hosting team with access to the server for support and maintenance purposes only. 

**CEB Inc** : provides GBG with a global talent assessment platform which is hosted in the US. As part of your application you may be requested to complete this assessment via a separate link. To generate this link, GBG will need to have shared your name and email address. The data entered is then determined by you.

**Other third parties**

Where you have engaged with an external recruitment agency they will have shared your details with GBG for a role they have notified you about. The recruitment agency also acts as a data controller.

We are unable to be more explicit in this statement as to who they are as we work with a large number of agencies globally. If you would like more information regarding your personal information, please contact us by email at compliance@gbgplc.com or by writing to: Privacy and Data Compliance, GBG, The Foundation, Chester Business Park, Chester, CH4 9GB.

We may also contact the named referee(s) you have supplied in order to provide a reference on you. Or once your application has been successful, your details may be shared with other third parties, such as a payroll provider. You will be notified of any further processing at the appropriate time.

**Accuracy of your personal information**

You enter your own information, so please ensure it is correct. If this needs to be updated, please contact behired@gbgplc.com who will be able to facilitate your request. 

**International data transfers**

As a global organisation, a transfer taking place will depend on where in the world you are based and the role you have applied for.

The platform on which be/hired is hosted by Access UK is in the United Kingdom, so if you only apply for a role in the European Economic Area (EEA) and do not complete a talent assessment, no international data transfer will have taken place. If you are in the EEA, and you do complete a talent assessment, your name and email address will have been transferred to CEB Inc., which is based in the US and is Privacy Shield certified.

Depending on the role you have applied for, we may need to transfer your personal information to other companies within GBG for administrative purposes. For example if you are based within the EEA, we may need to transfer your personal information outside of the EEA if you have applied for a role in a non-EEA country/territory.

**Your rights**

Please see the section on ‘Your rights under the GDPR’.
